Guide to the Batya Weinbaum papers, 1960-2015 RL.11482
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Batya Weinbaum papers
1960-2015
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
Weinbaum, Batya
RL.11482
46.5 Linear Feet 82 boxes
1.4 Gigabytes
Batya Weinbaum is a Jewish American artist, musician, poet, author, editor and professor. In addition to founding and editing the interdisciplinary feminist journal Femspec, she has published 17 books and more than 250 articles, poems, essays and reviews. She has made significant contributions to the fields of multiculturalism, women's studies, sexuality studies and education. The Batya Weinbaum papers consist of 83 boxes, spanning the years 1960-2015, and document a significant portion of her personal and professional history. The collection contains substantial materials related to Weinbaum's writing and research, including drafts of her books, materials related to the journal Femspec, and several decades of journals and sketchbooks.
Biographical / Historical
Batya Weinbaum is an artist, musician, poet, author, editor and professor. She was born Betty Susan Weinbaum in 1952 in Ann Arbor, Michigan. Her parents, Barbara Hyman and Jack Gerald Weinbaum, were activists during the Civil Rights Movement and passed on much of their social consciousness to their daughter.
Weinbaum received her bachelor's degree in Photography from Hampshire College in 1976. After graduation, she traveled across Latin America working as a documentary photographer. While in Chile, she witnessed Salvador Allende's Unidad Popular socialist movement. These experiences led to the publication of her first book, The Curious Courtship of Women and Socialism (South End Press), in 1978. Her photography documents the struggles of women fighting for freedom on the world stage, most notably in South America, China and Israel.
After returning to the United States, Weinbaum went on to receive her Master's degree from SUNY Buffalo in 1986, where she studied ethnomusicology and began painting and composing music based on myths about feminist utopias. Her theories about matriarchal music were published in the book Sounding Off! (Autonomedia, 1995). She became a member of the Vermont Composers Consortium and was an artist in residence at University of Illinois at Champaign Urbana.
Weinbaum received a PhD from the Interdisciplinary American Studies Program (housed in the Department of English) at the University of Massachusetts at Amherst in 1996. She conducted her dissertation research on Isla Mujeres, Mexico. She later published her thesis as a book, Islands of Women and Amazons: Representations and Realities (University of Texas Press, 2000). It was on Isla Mujeres that she gave birth to her daughter Ola Liota in 1992. The experience of having a child led Weinbaum to write several poetry collections, a collection of fiction titled Post Modern Motherhood, and found the Feminist Mothers and Their Allies Task Force in the National Women's Studies Association.
In 1997, Weinbaum founded a peer-review feminist journal, Femspec, an interdisciplinary feminist journal dedicated to science fiction, fantasy, magic realism, surrealism, myth, folklore and the supernatural. From 1998 to 2003, at Cleveland State University, Weinbaum received her first tenure track position teaching courses in English and multicultural literature. She filed a wrongful termination suit against the University in 2004. The case was settled in January 2006.
Following the resolution of the case, Weinbaum taught as a peripatetic educator teaching speech and debate and organizing literary events in Ohio. She was also a visiting faculty member and curriculum adviser at Pacifica Graduate Institute from 2006 to 2007. This position led to a teaching career based on distance learning at a variety of institutions including: Gaia University, Tiffin University, and SUNY New York. Weinbaum currently lives in Cleveland Heights, Ohio. She is still Editor-and-Chief of Femspec.
Content Description
This collection documents Weinbaum's personal life, education and professional life. The Batya Weinbaum papers are arranged into the following thirteen series: Legal, Correspondence, Press, Activities, Research and Scholarship, Art, Writing, Teaching, Photography, Print Materials, Journals, Family Memorabilia and Audiovisual Materials.
The first series largely documents Weinbuam's lawsuit against Cleveland State University from 2004-2006. The second series contains correspondence primarily related to Weinbaim's teaching and publications, but also has personal correspondence and letters she exchanged with influential figures in various fields such as contemporary American literature, multiculturalism, women's studies, poetry, music composition and education. The third and fourth series include press and reviews related to Weinbaum's personal writings and artwork, as well as items associated with workshops, speaking engagements and other activities given or attended by Weinbaum. The next four series contain substantial materials related to Weinbaum's writing and research, including: drafts of her books, poetry, academic publications, artwork, music and materials related to editing and publishing the journal FemSpec. The Teaching series also encompasses syllabi and course materials used during Weinbaum's time as a graduate student instructor and as a professional at Cleveland State University and Pacifica Graduate Institute.
The collection also includes an extensive Photography series, with photographs/negatives Weinbaum took professionally as a documentary photographer in South America and Mexico; fieldwork in China and Israel, as well as family photo albums and scrapbooks. The eleventh series contains several decades of journals, notebooks and sketchbooks. The Family Memorabilia series documents Weinbaum's relationship with her daughter, Ola Liota Weinbaum. The Audiovisual Materials series has electronic files in a variety of formats including: floppy discs, cassettes, CD-ROMs, DVD-ROMs and VHS tapes. These files encompass Weinbaum's writing and material related to FemSpec. The contents of Weinbuam's hard drive are also described throughout the series where appropriate. Where possible, Weinbuam's original folder titles and descriptions have been retained.
Provenance
The Batya Weinbaum papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a purchase in 2014.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection contains electronic records that must be requested through the collection guide and accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services with questions.
Women's studies -- Study and teaching; Women -- Education (Higher); Women authors; Women poets; Motherhood- United States; Women artists -- United States; Science fiction -- Authorship; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
- Legal Documentation, 1978-2012; 1
  Conditions Governing Access
  Series contains electronic records that must be requested through the collection guide and accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services with questions.
  - Author's permissions - release and copyright, 1998-2012 (Box 1)
  - Handwritten case notes (Box 1)
  - Grounds for grievance, 2012-01-16 (Box 1)
  - Sex Discrimination Archer, 2001-04 (Box 1)
  - Disability file (Box 1)
  - Batya pay analysis (Box 1)
  - Request to review, 2002 (Box 1)
  - EEOC- Questionnaire (Box 1)
  - EEOC- ADA Questionnaire (Box 1)
  - Termination of Medicaid (Box 1)
  - Payment for legal services, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Comment on Jones Case by retired colleague (Box 1)
  - Plaintiff Disbursement, 2005 (Box 1)
  - OCRC Public Records Request, 2002 (Box 1)
  - CSU Requests to Input on Service (Box 1)
  - Unauthorized web posting, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Request for Production of Documents to Defendant (Box 1)
  - CSU Memorandum on Batya's behavior, 2001-10-12 (Box 1)
  - CSU Pre-Disciplinary Conference Fact-Finding Report, 2003-08-19 (Box 1)
  - Research for appeal (Box 1)
  - Summary of Claim Against CSU (Box 1)
  - Deposition, 1998-07 (Box 1)
  - Responses to Ola's presence in class (Box 1)
  - CSU AAUP Grievance Form draft, 2002 (Box 1)
  - CSU Contract of Employment, 1998-05-15 (Box 1)
  - Adrienne Gosselin- research (Box 2)
  - Gary Dyer- research (Box 2)
  - Robert Krebs- research, 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Court transcript, 2005 (Box 2)
  - CSU Summary of Disparate Treatment (Box 2)
  - Comparable cases (Box 2)
  - Ohio Revised Code 4112.99 (Box 2)
  - Raising money, 2005-01-10 (Box 2)
  - William Chisholm-research, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - David Richardson- research (Box 3)
  - Neil Chandler- research, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Case testimony transcript (Box 4)
  - CSU Memorandum Recommendation of Non-Reappointment, 2002 (Box 4)
  - CSU Memorandum Declining Level IV Meeting, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Book Royalties, 2005-2006 (Box 4)
  - FBI file (Box 4)
  - CSU hiring documents (Box 4)
  - Batya testimony (Box 4)
  - Promises made by chair (Box 4)
  - CSU discriminatory actions, 1978-1979 (Box 4)
  - UT Press receipt- additional copies of book, 2000 (Box 4)
  - UT Press agreement, 2001 (Box 4)
  - Publication contracts, 1994-2000 (Box 4)
  - Faculty reviews for lawsuit (Box 4)
  - Case file (Box 4)
  - Case file electronic records, 2003-2011; 205 document files; approximately 15 MB. (Digital-materials RL11482-SET-0001)
  - Batya CSU chronology (Box 4)
- Correspondence, 1963-2015; 2
  - Lori corresondence, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Vermont Composers Consortium, 1989 (Box 5)
  - Faculty Awards, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Letter of recommendation- Cassandra Taylor (Box 5)
  - Letter of recommendation- Rhoda Crowder (Box 5)
  - Multi-Ethnic Literature Concentration, 2000-2001 (Box 5)
  - Letter from Allen Ginsberg's office, 1991-09-10 (Box 5)
  - Kurt Vonnegut letter, 1983 (Box 5)
  - Karen Steckol correspondence, 2000 (Box 5)
  - Postcards from Bernardo (Box 5)
  - Calls for papers (Box 5)
  - Peer review correspondence, 1999-2001 (Box 5)
  - Case correspondence, 2001-2002 (Box 5)
  - Academic correspondence, 1994-2015 (Box 5)
  - Women's Studies job search, 1999-2000 (Box 5)
  - Women's Studies search committee (Box 5)
  - University of Michigan Post-Doc Fellowship, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Cover letters, 1995-2007 (Box 5)
  - Letters of recommendation (Box 5)
  - Pacifica Institute students correspondence, 2007 (Box 5)
  - Lakeland Community College application, 2010 (Box 5)
  - Personal correspondence, 1963-1969 (Box 6)
  - Personal correspondence, 1970-1979 (Box 6)
  - Postcards, 1980-1989 (Box 6)
  - Personal corespondence, 1980-1989 (Box 6)
  - Postcards, 1990-1999 (Box 6)
  - Personal correspondence, 1990-1995 (Box 6)
  - Personal correspondence, 1996-1999 (Box 6)
  - Postcards, 2000-2015 (Box 6)
  - Personal correspondence, 2000-2015 (Box 6)
  - Personal correspondence, undated (Box 7)
  - Postcards, undated (Box 7)
  - FEMSPEC correspondence (Box 7)
  - FEMSPEC support letters, 1999-2000 (Box 7)
  - FEMSPEC year-end subscription letter, 1999-2000 (Box 7)
  - Batik correspondence, 2004-2006 (Box 7)
  - Publication correspondence, 1995-2003 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence electronic records, 2004-2011; 170 document files; approximately 6 MB. (Digital-materials RL11482-SET-0001)
- Press, 1983-2013; 3
  - Articles on Clothespin Fever Press (Box 8)
  - Old Lesbians Organizing for Change, 2013 (Box 8)
  - What She Wants- Article about peace activist (Box 8)
  - Barbara Weinbaum articles (Box 8)
  - Donated to the Lesbian History Archives (Box 8)
  - Alix Shulman write-up, 1997 (Box 8)
  - 3 Wednesdays of Women's Events (Box 8)
  - Waves for Peace- matriarchal music making (Box 8)
  - Golden Poet Award, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Vermont Composers Festival, 1989-11 (Box 8)
  - CSU budget revision articles (Box 8)
  - Book reviews- Dreams in a Minor Key (Box 8)
  - The Weinbaum Award: Honoring Jack Weinbaum, 1977 (Box 8)
  - Neighborhood People: Batya Weinbaum in Washington Market (Box 8)
  - Reviews- Un-beating the Beat Women (Box 8)
  - Book reviews- Islands of Women and Amazons (Box 8)
  - Book reviews- The Nightmares of Sasha Weitzwoman (Box 8)
  - Who's Who contribution, 2003-09 (Box 8)
  - Music of the Sea: Movement for the Ancestors, 1987 (Box 8)
  - Promo for The Nightmares of Sasha Weitzwoman (Box 8)
  - Sheldon Swope Art Gallery building campaign (Box 8)
  - Interview- Theory is fun?, 1979-09 (Box 8)
  - Cochin, India Medical Sciences Research Center (Box 8)
  - Retrospective Mixed Media Show, 2008 (Box 8)
  - MCEC Resolve it Together certificate, 2009 (Box 8)
  - Explore the feminine divine (Box 8)
  - Contemporary Authors, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Salute to Feminists in the Visual Arts, 2003-11-06 (Box 8)
  - CSU Women Who Make a Difference, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Poets and Writers Literary Showcase, 2002 (Box 8)
  - Planned Parenthood- Bobbie Weinbaum (Box 8)
  - Book reviews- The Curious Courtship of Women's Liberation and Socialism (Box 8)
  - Book reviews- The Island of Floating Women (Box 8)
  - Poetry contest honorable mention, 1990-03-22 (Box 8)
  - Book reviews- Tales of Magic Realism by Women (Box 8)
  - Book reviews- Pictures of Patriarchy (Box 8)
  - Book reviews- Fragments of Motherhood (Box 8)
  - Press release- The Island of Floating Women, 1993-08 (Box 8)
  - CSU Readings and events (Box 8)
  - Subscription- West End Magazine (Box 8)
  - Articles about court case (Box 8)
  - Articles on FEMSPEC (Box 8)
  - CSU The Bridge, 1998-2001 (Box 8)
  - Merchandise price list (Box 8)
  - Announcements- Book talks and presentatons (Box 8)
  - Reviews- Short writings (Box 8)
  - Announcement- Opening Palms Vol. 2 (Box 80)
  - Interview with Lizzie Borden, 1988 (Box 80)
  - Mental "Illness" article, 1983 (Box 80)
  - Announcement- Voices from the Kibbutz (Box 80)
- Activities and Events, 1968-2012; 4
  - Satchidananda Ashram Yogaville (Box 9)
  - Kibbutz, 1999; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - New College of California Women's Spirituality M.A. (Box 9)
  - Civilization of the Goddess, 1997-10 (Box 9)
  - Pagan Pride Day (Box 9)
  - Mother Goddesses of India tour, 2006 (Box 9)
  - OLOC Action Group (Box 9)
  - Kingswood Reunion Class of 1970 (Box 9)
  - Lesbian communities (Box 9)
  - Association for the Study of Women and Mythology, 2012 (Box 9)
  - Conference invitations (Box 9)
  - CSU Counseling Center (Box 9)
  - Gay and lesbian peer listening line (Box 9)
  - Angela Davis petition to CSU (Box 9)
  - Rowe Camp and Conference Center, 2012 (Box 9)
  - Cultural Competency Diversity Conference, 1999-10-22 (Box 9)
  - Cleveland College of Jewish Studies (Box 9)
  - Reclamation Project (Box 9)
  - CSU study acting (Box 9)
  - Women's Community Foundation, 2000 (Box 9)
  - NWSA Conference, 2000 (Box 9)
  - Notes for conference proposals (Box 9)
  - Jack Kerouac Conference, 1995-06-04 (Box 9)
  - Notes from the first year, 1968-06 (Box 9)
  - Science Fiction and Fantasy Area Panel, 2000-04 (Box 9)
  - MELUS Conference, 2001-03-01 (Box 9)
  - Student Award Nominations, 2000 (Box 9)
  - Modern Language Association Annual Meeting, 1995 (Box 9)
  - Landdyke electronic records, 2005-2011; 16 document and image files; approximately 1 MB. (Digital-materials RL11482-SET-0001)
  - Palm Reading electronic records, 2004-2011; 4 document files; approximately 1 MB. (Digital-materials RL11482-SET-0001)
- Research and Scholarship, 1961-2011; 5
  - Research for comps. exams doctoral level (Box 10)
  - Graduate course Beat Literature, 1990 (Box 10)
  - Graduate course Material Culture, 1990 (Box 10)
  - Notes- Marge Piercy (Box 10)
  - Linda Einstein- The Names of the Beast, 1996 (Box 10)
  - Raymond- Reproductive Technologies (Box 10)
  - Islands- Annotated Bibliography (Box 10)
  - Echols- Daring to be Bad (Box 10)
  - Firestone (Box 10)
  - Ursula LeGuin- The Carrier-Bag Theory (Box 10)
  - Michelle Wallace- Black Macho (Box 10)
  - Notes- For Colored Girls (Box 10)
  - Shulman- Burning Questions (Box 10)
  - The Combahee River Collective Statement, 1974 (Box 10)
  - Historicizing the Hula (Box 10)
  - Graduate student papers (Box 10)
  - Graduate course English Folklore (Box 10)
  - Island Image (Box 10)
  - Notes- Campbell Oriental Myth (Box 10)
  - Notes- Women in Search of Utopia (Box 10)
  - Island references gathered while reading (Box 10)
  - Herland or Ourland: Feminist Utopias as Models for Social Change (Box 10)
  - Notes- The Wanderground (Box 10)
  - Notes- Turner New World (Box 10)
  - Herland (Box 10)
  - Nights HD Siren's Island Image, 1986 (Box 10)
  - Virgin as Archetype (Box 10)
  - Commentary- Simone, David, Campbell, Rich and Johhnston (Box 10)
  - Island poetry (Box 10)
  - Myths of Women in Meso America, 1992-04 (Box 10)
  - Miscellaneous bibliography (Box 10)
  - Leslie Stone- The Man With Four Dimensional Eyes (Box 11)
  - Leslie Stone- The Rape of the Solar System (Box 11)
  - Leslie Stone- Gulliver, 3000 A.D. (Box 11)
  - Leslie Stone- The Great Ones (Box 11)
  - Leslie Stone- From the Moon (Box 11)
  - Leslie Stone- Across the Void (Box 11)
  - Leslie Stone- Cosmic Joke (Box 11)
  - Leslie Stone- The Day of the Pulps (Box 11)
  - Erin Addison- Saving Other Women from Other Men (Box 11)
  - Ruth Finnegan- Literacy and Orality (Box 11)
  - "A Las Mujeres" (Box 11)
  - Whoopi Goldberg- Artemis in Dreadlocks (Box 11)
  - Writing method exercises (Box 11)
  - Jews, Multiculturalism and Boasian Anthropology, 1998 (Box 11)
  - Recovering Zora Neale Hurston's Work (Box 11)
  - Joanne Morreale- Xena Warrior Princess (Box 11)
  - Ethnography Unbound (Box 11)
  - Context and Continuities: An Intro to Women's Experimental Fiction (Box 11)
  - Lynette Carpenter- There's No Place Like Home (Box 11)
  - Women and Hip Hop, 1997 (Box 11)
  - C. Nadia Seremetakis- The Last Word (Box 11)
  - Wachter bibliography, 1997 (Box 11)
  - Women and folk music bibliography (Box 11)
  - Experimental women writers bibliography (Box 11)
  - Native American bibliography, 1999 (Box 11)
  - Latina bibliography (Box 11)
  - African praise poetry (Box 11)
  - Classics research (Box 11)
  - Otto Rank- The Double (Box 12)
  - Two novels by Robbe-Grillet (Box 12)
  - Mary Firestone- The Vision and Persecution of Aurora Phelps (Box 12)
  - Women in Science Fiction annotated bibliography (Box 12)
  - Leslie Stone book proposal (Box 12)
  - Leslie Stone- Wonder Stories Story Critiques (Box 12)
  - Richard A. Lupoff- Clare Winger Harris (Box 12)
  - Great science fiction about doctors (Box 12)
  - Rationale for science fiction as a literature option (Box 12)
  - Notes- science fiction articles (Box 12)
  - Eric Drown- dissertation abstract (Box 12)
  - David H. Keller bibliography, 2005 (Box 12)
  - Susana J. Sturgis- What's A P.C. Feminist Like You Doing in a Fantasy Like This? (Box 12)
  - Women world writers (Box 12)
  - Sepratist fantasies and single-sex societies bibliographies (Box 12)
  - Wonder Women (Box 12)
  - Science Fiction and Fantasy: A Checklist (Box 12)
  - Pamela Sargent- More Women of Wonder (Box 12)
  - David H. Keller- The Feminine Metamorphosis (Box 12)
  - Leif Davin- The Age of Wonder (Box 12)
  - Science fiction bibliographies (Box 12)
  - Donald M. Hassler- Comic Tones in Science Fiction (Box 12)
  - Groff Conklin on pulps (Box 12)
  - John W. Campbell Jr. - Concerning Science Fiction (Box 12)
  - Teresa Elbert- The Convergence of Post-Mordern Innovative Fiction and Science Fiction, 1980 (Box 12)
  - Jane Donawerth- Lilith Lorraine: Feminist Socialist Writer in the Pulps (Box 12)
  - Dorothy Scarborough- War and the Supernatureal in Literature (Box 12)
  - Wonder Stories favorite authors (Box 12)
  - Gary Westfahl- Popular Tradition of Science Fiction Criticism, 1999 (Box 12)
  - Comparison of two Stone papers, 1994 (Box 12)
  - Leslie Stone- Death Dallies Awhile (Box 12)
  - Leslie Stone- When the Flame Flowers Blossomed (Box 12)
  - Leslie Stone- Gravity Off! (Box 12)
  - Leslie Stone- Fall of Mercury (Box 12)
  - Leslie Stone- Through the Veil (Box 12)
  - Notes- Marxism (Box 13)
  - Notes- Steve Reich biography (Box 13)
  - Oral poetry research (Box 13)
  - Oral poetry (Box 13)
  - Issues in collecting women's life stories (Box 13)
  - Latino research (Box 13)
  - Jewish research (Box 13)
  - Girls anime research (Box 13)
  - Hula dance research (Box 13)
  - Arabic dance research (Box 13)
  - Notes- dance and Japan (Box 13)
  - Women in Traditional Chinese Literature (Box 13)
  - The Black Saint's Epitaph (Box 13)
  - Notes- graduate coursework (Box 13)
  - Notes- music history (Box 13)
  - The Music of Pauline Oliveros (Box 13)
  - Marina Roseman- The Social Structuring of Sound (Box 13)
  - Steven Field- Sound Structure as Social Structure (Box 13)
  - The State of Music- Why Composers Write (Box 13)
  - Notes- music and noise (Box 13)
  - Music and healing bibliography (Box 13)
  - Egyptian music research (Box 13)
  - NWSA file, 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Feminist publishing articles (Box 14)
  - William Partridge- The Hippie Ghetto (Box 14)
  - Feminist Motherhood Roundtable, 1996 (Box 14)
  - Lani Ravin- Childcare Policies in the U.S. (Box 14)
  - Cultural diversity bibliography (Box 14)
  - Kate Kruckemeyer- The Isn't Supposed to Happen, 1998 (Box 14)
  - AAA Statement on Race (Box 14)
  - Notes- learning styles (Box 14)
  - Gerald Graff- Conflict in the classroom articles (Box 14)
  - Kathie Sarachild- Consciousness Raising: A Radical Weapon (Box 14)
  - African American films in area libraries (Box 14)
  - Multiple Reflections on Child Abuse (Box 14)
  - Victimized Daughters: Sexual Violence and the Empathic Female Self (Box 14)
  - Notes- oral history (Box 14)
  - Notes- Burroughs (Box 15)
  - William Burroughs- Letter to Allen Ginsberg (Box 15)
  - Anne Waldman- Fast Speaking Woman (Box 15)
  - Black Harlem in poetry (Box 15)
  - Allen Ginsberg- photo and articles (Box 15)
  - Flights of Fancy: Armed Conflict in Science Fiction and Fantasy (Box 15)
  - John Rodden- Orwell on Religion (Box 15)
  - Irene M. class paper- The Last Woman Compared to the Conquest of Gola, 2000 (Box 15)
  - Brian Dunn class paper- Defining "Jew": Jewish Fantasy and Science Fiction, 2000 (Box 15)
  - Leslie Stone- Letter of the Twenty-Fourth Century (Box 15)
  - Karen Lopes class paper- Gola and the Moon Mistress, 1994 (Box 15)
  - Andy Duncan ICFA paper- A Different Species (Box 15)
  - Delflair- Thanor (Box 15)
  - Leslie Stone- Wonder Stories and Transcripts (Box 15)
  - Notes- Jews and science fiction (Box 15)
  - Science Fiction by 20th c. Jews book proposal (Box 15)
  - Leslie Stone book proposal (Box 15)
  - Notes- Richard Wright (Box 15)
  - Women's salons research (Box 15)
  - Notes- Wonder Stories (Box 15)
  - Early paper on Leslie Stone (Box 15)
  - Leslie Stone biography and notes (Box 15)
  - List of maps (Box 16)
  - Native American literature (Box 16)
  - Notes- history of Arabian music (Box 16)
  - Gertrude Stein- What Are Masterpieces (Box 16)
  - Notes- music and emotion (Box 16)
  - Beats & Company list of books (Box 16)
  - Notes- John Clelloy Holmes (Box 16)
  - Ann Charters- Go (Box 16)
  - Notes- Joyce Johnson Minor Characters (Box 16)
  - Jones- Preface to Suicide Poems (Box 16)
  - Notes- Kerouac (Box 16)
  - Beats fortune cookies (Box 16)
  - Black poetry relationship to the Beats (Box 16)
  - Notes- Beat essays in critical literature (Box 16)
  - Notes- Ferlinghetti biographies (Box 16)
  - Carolyn Cassady- Off the Road (Box 16)
  - Maggie Cassidy- Jack Kerouac (Box 16)
  - Jack Kerouac- The Subterraneans (Box 16)
  - Donald Sobol- The Amazons of Greek Mythology (Box 16)
  - Lorna Hardwick- Ancient Amazons: Heroes, Outsiders, or Women? (Box 16)
  - Homer as "scripture" (Box 16)
  - Charles Boer- The Homeric Hymns (Box 16)
  - Notes- classical poetry (Box 16)
  - Notes- Nagy poetry as performance (Box 16)
  - Beth Anderson- Report From the Front, 1979 (Box 16)
  - Notes- Japanese mythology (Box 16)
  - Stanislaw Lem- Metafantasia (Box 16)